Nature unleashed
Ice Quake is a science fiction, action, thriller film directed by Paul Ziller.
As the permafrost melts in Alaska, underground rivers of volatile liquid
methane form which sets off a series of devastating earthquakes.
Forced apart by this violent occurrence, one family must find each other during the holidays
and work to stop the deadly rivers that could cause a worldwide catastrophy.
Michael Webster, played by Brendan Fehr.
Emily Webster, played by Holly Dignard.
Tia Webster, played by Jodelle Ferland.
Shane Webster, played by Ryan Grantham.
Bruce Worthington, played by Rob LaBelle.
Ram, played by Nicholas Carella.
Ice Quake, also called Ice Quake: Nature Unleashed, is a 2010 television action film
written by David Ray and directed by Paul Ziller and shown on the Syfy channel.
It stars Brendan Fehr, Holly Dignard, Jodelle
Ferland, Ryan Grantham and Rob LaBelle.
Set primarily in Alaska, the film follows the members of a
family caught amidst a natural disaster.
As the permafrost thaws, subterranean rivers of liquid methane and disastrous
earthquakes are unleashed, threatening to lead the Earth to a catastrophic end.
The film explores themes of earthquake, disaster movie,
exploding helicopter, christmas season, snow and ice.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.